Senior Software Developer

To take up challenge project and responsibilities completing it successfully with innovative thinking and to work for the growth and prosperity of company, team and self. I have wo king experience in PHP, Laravel and Node express and interested to explore this journey.

SKILLS

- Strong In Core PHP
- PHP Framework: Laravel, Symfony, Slim, ZEND
- PHP CMS: WordPress, Drupal
- Databases: MySQL, PostgreSQL
- Node.JS, Angular.JS
- HTML5, CSS, JavaScript & JQuery Libraries
- Good Knowledge In Agile Methodology,
- Good in GIT Flow

WORK HISTORY

Overall Experience: 12 + yrs

2022 Mar – 2023 May	Strive PVT LTD, Pondicherry Worked in internal projects Technologies: Laravel, core PHP, angular V11, MYSQL Role: Senior PHP Developer, Team Member Responsibility: New enhancement and Fixing issues in existing Projects. Altered existing logic and make code reusability and reduced the process overall time taken and successfully deployed in live users. Converted backup processes from php code into MySQL Stored Procedures and added event to handle the backup process to reduce CRON jobs. Upgraded PHP version in existing Projects. Tracking changes and documented for future reference, Apache Log maintenance, Log Daily activity and issue fixes in Jira
2019 Aug – 2022 Jan	KinStart PVT LTD, Sivakangai ChannelHub Technologies: Node.js - Express Framework, Angular, POSTGRES Role: Backend Developer Responsibility: Convert Large SQL quires into stored procedures Added Lasy load in search page & S3 Buckets for upload documents Implemented Payment gateway (stripe)

Senior Software Developer

	☐ Added Validation in Excel using VBA to make easy
	upload in website from user login. Integrated Third
	party tools.
	Involved in payment & result Pages UI development in angular.
	☐ Added Notification module using web sockets to send
	and receive message from user <> admin.
	☐ Fix Issues posted in Jira and close the issue on time
	☐ Maintain API postman collection ON edit or add
	 Properly maintained DB Migration on new table creation, seed or existing alteration.
	☐ Performed scrum based work method
2015 Nov to 2019	IHorse PVT LTD,
July	Pondicherry GTC
	Technologies: Angular V2, Ionic, Cordova, CSS Delay Full Clast Benedation
	Role: Full Stack Developer Roam and Hilliam
	Responsibility: Handled individually fully from development to app
	release in both Android and IOS environments.
	☐ Clone project from existing and made need changes,
	coordinate with Project Delivery Head to collect
	requirements
	☐ Unit Test app in different model mobiles and fixes issues
	☐ Responded to Client Quires, Version Upgrades and
	support for existing app
	IHorse PVT LTD,
	Pondicherry
	DooPaaDoo
	 Technologies: Node.JS, Angular, JavaScript, CSS Role: Backend Support
	Role: Backend Support Responsibility:
	☐ Changed video Player from existing one,
	☐ Worked in enhancement like Added online context
	pages, added pages for upcoming videos and event
	and Bug Fixing
	☐ Added Ads in the video using VMap , VAST XML
	IHorse PVT LTD,
	Pondicherry
	HealthEnabler
	Technologies: Concrete5 CMS
	Role: Developer
	Responsibility: Responsibility:
	☐ Block Creation,
	☐ Edit existing Feature in the CMS added Social icons
	and like buttons Interact client and collect the
	requirements and complete it on time

Senior Software Developer

	 IHorse PVT LTD, Pondicherry Mobifret Technologies: Laravel, PostgreSQL Role: Senior PHP Developer Responsibility: □ Database design, □ Worked in Admin Panel Development , Handled Unit Test and fix issue posted in JIRA □ Documentation and Logging task in Jira
2012 Nov. 2015 Nov.	ECR Systems & Solutions But 1 td
2013 Nov - 2015 Nov	EGB Systems & Solutions Pvt. Ltd, Chennai Epadasalai Technologies: symphony, SVN, HTML, CSS, JavaScript Role: Senior PHP Developer Responsibility: □ Involved from initial development . □ Worked in major modules like subject module, fees structure model and Assessment module. □ Followed Scrum based Work method □ Used SVN code version
Jul 2012 2012 Nov	Takasaanaa DVT LTD. Bandiabarny
Jul 2012 -2013 Nov	Tekessence PVT LTD, Pondicherry
Jul 2012 -2013 Nov	IdealTraids
Jul 2012 -2013 Nov	
Jul 2012 -2013 Nov	IdealTraids
Jul 2012 -2013 Nov	IdealTraids Technologies: Zend Framework, Mysql Role: Programmer Analyst
Jul 2012 -2013 Nov	IdealTraids Technologies: Zend Framework, Mysql Role: Programmer Analyst Responsibility:
Jul 2012 -2013 Nov	 IdealTraids Technologies: Zend Framework, Mysql Role: Programmer Analyst Responsibility: □ Enhancement in existing project,
Jul 2012 -2013 Nov	 IdealTraids Technologies: Zend Framework, Mysql Role: Programmer Analyst Responsibility: Enhancement in existing project, Added PayPal payment in existing project,
Jul 2012 -2013 Nov	 IdealTraids Technologies: Zend Framework, Mysql Role: Programmer Analyst Responsibility: Enhancement in existing project, Added PayPal payment in existing project, Integrating 3rd part recruitment tools,
Jul 2012 -2013 Nov	 IdealTraids Technologies: Zend Framework, Mysql Role: Programmer Analyst Responsibility: Enhancement in existing project, Added PayPal payment in existing project, Integrating 3rd part recruitment tools, Added Online Assessment Module,
Jul 2012 -2013 Nov	IdealTraids Technologies: Zend Framework, Mysql Role: Programmer Analyst Responsibility: Enhancement in existing project, Added PayPal payment in existing project, Integrating 3 rd part recruitment tools, Added Online Assessment Module, Added jQuery dataTable in the result pages to make it
Jul 2012 -2013 Nov	IdealTraids Technologies: Zend Framework, Mysql Role: Programmer Analyst Responsibility:
Jul 2012 -2013 Nov	IdealTraids Technologies: Zend Framework, Mysql Role: Programmer Analyst Responsibility: Enhancement in existing project, Added PayPal payment in existing project, Integrating 3 rd part recruitment tools, Added Online Assessment Module, Added jQuery dataTable in the result pages to make it
	IdealTraids Technologies: Zend Framework, Mysql Role: Programmer Analyst Responsibility: Enhancement in existing project, Added PayPal payment in existing project, Integrating 3 rd part recruitment tools, Added Online Assessment Module, Added jQuery dataTable in the result pages to make it faster search and download Got Client appreciation email for result module development
	IdealTraids Technologies: Zend Framework, Mysql Role: Programmer Analyst Responsibility: Enhancement in existing project, Added PayPal payment in existing project, Integrating 3 rd part recruitment tools, Added Online Assessment Module, Added jQuery dataTable in the result pages to make it faster search and download Got Client appreciation email for result module development Software Developers of India,
	IdealTraids Technologies: Zend Framework, Mysql Role: Programmer Analyst Responsibility: Enhancement in existing project, Added PayPal payment in existing project, Integrating 3 rd part recruitment tools, Added Online Assessment Module, Added jQuery dataTable in the result pages to make it faster search and download Got Client appreciation email for result module development Software Developers of India, Pondicherry Travref
	IdealTraids Technologies: Zend Framework, Mysql Role: Programmer Analyst Responsibility: Enhancement in existing project, Added PayPal payment in existing project, Integrating 3 rd part recruitment tools, Added Online Assessment Module, Added jQuery dataTable in the result pages to make it faster search and download Got Client appreciation email for result module development Software Developers of India,
	IdealTraids Technologies: Zend Framework, Mysql Role: Programmer Analyst Responsibility: Enhancement in existing project, Added PayPal payment in existing project, Integrating 3 rd part recruitment tools, Added Online Assessment Module, Added jQuery dataTable in the result pages to make it faster search and download Got Client appreciation email for result module development Software Developers of India, Pondicherry Travref
	IdealTraids Technologies: Zend Framework, Mysql Role: Programmer Analyst Responsibility:
	IdealTraids Technologies: Zend Framework, Mysql Role: Programmer Analyst Responsibility: Added PayPal payment in existing project, Integrating 3 rd part recruitment tools, Added Online Assessment Module, Added jQuery dataTable in the result pages to make it faster search and download Got Client appreciation email for result module development Software Developers of India, Pondicherry Travref Technologies: HTML, CSS, JavaScript Role: Programmer Analyst
	IdealTraids Technologies: Zend Framework, Mysql Role: Programmer Analyst Responsibility: Enhancement in existing project, Added PayPal payment in existing project, Integrating 3 rd part recruitment tools, Added Online Assessment Module, Added jQuery dataTable in the result pages to make it faster search and download Got Client appreciation email for result module development Software Developers of India, Pondicherry Travref Technologies: HTML, CSS, JavaScript Role: Programmer Analyst Responsibility:
	IdealTraids Technologies: Zend Framework, Mysql Role: Programmer Analyst Responsibility: Added PayPal payment in existing project, Added PayPal payment in existing project, Integrating 3rd part recruitment tools, Added Online Assessment Module, Added jQuery dataTable in the result pages to make it faster search and download Got Client appreciation email for result module development Software Developers of India, Pondicherry Travref Technologies: HTML, CSS, JavaScript Role: Programmer Analyst Responsibility: Load Map routes via JSON data, Testing and

Senior Software Developer

Dec 2009 - Jan 2012	Perfect Innovation, Pondicherry Internal Projects
	 Technologies: Core PHP, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, VBA, WordPress
	Role: Junior Programmer
	Responsibility:
	□ Worked in Billing management,
	☐ Handles Individually in Online recruitment process
	for government sector and complete it
	successfully.
	☐ Tax sheet generation for employee for employee using VBA

- Worked in More than 30 projects.
- Handling PHP & Laravel Training FITA Academy since 2021
- Worked in Payment Gateway's (Stripe, PayPal)
- Good Knowledge in AWS concepts in S3, Load Balancer and EC2 concepts
- Interested to learn new technologies.
- Good in Oral and written communication

EDUCATION

Master of Science in computer science from Annamalai University in 2019 with First Class – **Distance Education**

Bachelor of Education from KAMLA COLLEGE OF EDUCATION, Thirunavalur, in 2018 with First Class -

Regular

Bachelor of Computer Application in 2007 from Pondicherry University Community college with First Class - **Regular**